Marina Orlova

Senior/Lead Full Stack Engineer | TS/React/Node | Remote

Spain +34 624 448 031 fuzzy.object@gmail.com

Citizenship: Netherlands

Linkedin

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Experienced Engineer, with nearly 20 years of experience in the IT industry, specializes in the modern JavaScript/TypeScript ecosystem creating high-quality, well-structured code and contributing to system designs and architecture. Complex problem-solver with analytical and driven mindset.

The career journey began with C/C++/Oracle development and advanced through various senior roles in software and data-warehouse projects.

Experienced in remote work, excelling in startup environments, and staying ahead with evolving technologies.

SKILLS

• Frontend: TypeScript, React, React-Query, Redux

• Backend: Node, Express, AWS SDK (S3, SQS, RDS)

Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Elasticsearch, Redis, Oracle, DynamoDB

• **DevOps**: Githab

Web3: Hardhat, Solidity
AI: Langchain, Langgraph
Others: PHP, Symfony

EXPERIENCE

Garden Computing, US (remote) - Full Stack Engineer

11/2024 - present

- Engineering open-source toolkit for sync & secure collaborative data.
- Joined as 5th software engineer in the team
- Contributed to SDK codebase design and optimization
- Performed refactoring on core packages of the library
- Tech stack: TypeScript, Node, React, Playwright.

Omnipresent, UK (remote) - Senior/Lead Stack Engineer

05/2021 - 05/2024

- Engineered applications and microservices for a dashboard used in both internal and client-facing roles for a global employment platform. Supported the streamlining of processes and improved interactions across our global hiring operations, all within a fully remote capacity.
- Tech stack: React, Node, TypeScript, PostgreSQL, DynamoDB, hosted on AWS.

Speakap, Amsterdam, Netherlands (hybrid) - Senior/Lead Full Stack Engineer 01/2019 - 04/2021

- Developed custom integrations with third-party solutions for the Speakap B2B social network platform, targeting services that had been integral to our clients' daily routines.
- Each integration was crafted as a widget, functioning as a small application that served as a proxy with third-party APIs.
- Tech stack: Node/React/MongoDB

Vliegtickets.nl, Amsterdam, Netherlands - Senior Full Stack Engineer

09/2018 - 12/2018

- Enhanced one of the largest airline tickets webshops in the Netherlands, focusing on improving the ticket booking experience
- Stack: Node, React/Redux, Cypress, Jest, Karma.

Endouble, Amsterdam, Netherlands - Full Stack Engineer

08/2016 - 08/2018

- Contributed in the development of a SaaS career platform.
- Stack: PHP7, Symfony3, Vanilla JS, React/Redux, DDD, Elasticsearch, PHPUnit, Behat, Docker, Ansible, Ant, Jenkins.

AppDaddy.com, Moscow, Russia - Senior Back-end/PHP developer

08/2015 - 07/2016

- Developed and maintained REST services for a multi-modular social network monitoring platform, enhancing system performance and reliability.
- Stack: Symfony 2, NGINX, Doctrine, MongoDB, AWS SDK, JavaScript, Angular JS.

Online store pelleteria.ru, Moscow, Russia - Co-founder / Founding Full Stack Engineer 12/2010 - 07/2015

 From inception to launch, developed an online store on Zend Framework, later migrating to Magento, overseeing all aspects of development and operations.

- Maintaining Magento store, Devops.
- Tech stack: Zend Framework, MySQL/Twig/HTML/JavaScript/JQuery

GlowByte Consulting, Moscow, Russia - Senior DWH Consultant

07/2007 - 04/2012

- Led DWH projects for mobile operators, from planning and development to team leadership.
- Worked on technical requirements, planning project stages, leading a development team, developing ETL processes.

R-Style Softlab, Moscow, Russia - C++ Developer

07/2005 - 04/2007

 Contributed to banking system projects, using C++/Oracle stack to deliver financial solutions.

EDUCATION

Bryansk State Technical University (BSTU) - Engineer in Computer Science

June 2005

ADDITIONAL

I am actively exploring Web3 technologies, with a focus on Ethereum and smart contracts. My interest has led me to experiment with ethers.js, and I have contributed to the development of an MVP for an NFT project, gaining practical experience in blockchain applications.